# Ainaa Sakinah Azman

## Software Engineer

■ ainaasakinah@gmail.com

in ainaasakinah

★ ainaasakinah.com

anotherainaa

Saku-shi, Nagano

#### **Profile**

I'm a full-stack software engineer with experience in JavaScript/Node.js, Ruby/Rails, SQL, Go, AWS, and React. I'm currently residing in Nagano on a Japanese spouse visa.

I recently built Conifer, an open-source framework that simplifies parallelizing Cypress tests on AWS infrastructure for local development.

#### **Technical Experience**

2022 — present Remote

## Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Conifer @

- Architected and created Conifer, an open-source framework that simplifies parallelizing Cypress tests on AWS infrastructure for local development
- Built a CLI to execute Conifer commands with Node.js, Commander.js, and Inquirer.js
- Utilized AWS CDK to allow users to dynamically deploy Conifer's AWS infrastructure (ECR, ECS, EC2, S3, DynamoDB)
- Utilized AWS SDK for JS within the user's containerized application to send test artifacts to S3 and metadata to DynamoDB
- Designed a test file splitting algorithm based on existing Cypress test timing data
- Reduced local Cypress test suite run time by up to 4x via parallelization & optimized test splitting
- Created a live dashboard for visualizing aggregated Cypress test results with Express,
   React and TailwindCSS which shows test execution results in real-time
- Incorporated an Agile approach in collaborating with a remote team of 4 engineers across 2 timezones which included daily standups, weekly sprints, and pair programming.
- Co-authored a comprehensive technical case study and presented a tech talk about Conifer's design decisions, architecture, and tradeoffs made while building Conifer

04.2019 - 08.2022 Remote

#### Student, Launch School ∂

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum, with progression, measured and gated by rigorous written exams and live coding interviews to develop problem-solving and technical skills.

#### Selected Projects:

- Neko Bin A RequestBin-like tool for inspecting webhooks (DO Droplet, Nginx, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars)
- Yello A Trello-like, Kanban-style project management app (MERN stack)
- Shopping Cart A database-backed e-commerce app (React, Redux, MongoDB, Node.js)

#### **Professional Experience**

02.2020 — 12.2020 Tokyo, Japan

#### Coding Curriculum Developer & Instructor, Saturday Kids Japan

 Created a brand-new curriculum introducing the concept of algorithms to kids using Scratch

06.2017 — 01.2020 Tokyo, Japan

#### Project Manager, Tacchi Studios

- Managed two of the studio's existing clients and collaborated extensively with clients to
  provide product-centric insights on the development and maintenance of their products.
- Facilitated requirement discussions for agile-based development.
- Collaborated with developers in performing UAT testing and reproducing bugs reliably which allowed for bugs to be fixed more easily and prevented several critical bugs from reaching production.

# 10.2019 Tokyo, Japan 10.2015 — 02.2017 Tokyo, Japan

## Teaching Assistant, Le Wagon Tokyo

- Assisted students in their coding challenges by reading error messages together and breaking down problems into smaller achievable pieces
- Facilitated use case discussions during the product design sprint

## Head Of Customer Service, MAHLE Trading Japan

- Managed a team of 4 based in 2 locations (Tokyo and Shanghai) and collaborated with the Sales team and APAC logistics in improving the delivery of orders
- Together with the entire team, we increased average monthly sales by 1.5x per month and reduced lead time from 6 months to 5 months

11.2014 — 09.2015 Tokyo, Japan

### Sales Assistant, MAHLE Trading Japan

 Used Excel formulas and functions to automate the creation of sales reports and automate repeatable sections of export documentation which allowed me to do the work that has historically taken 2 employees to do

#### **Technical Skills**

#### Languages

JavaScript, Ruby, Go, SQL, HTML, CSS

#### Cloud

AWS (DynamoDB, ECS, EC2, S3, Lambda, IAM), DigitalOcean (Droplets)

#### **Frameworks**

React/Redux, Express, Sinatra, Rails, Handlebars

#### **Other Tools**

Git/GitHub, Docker, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful APIs, Webhooks, SSH

## **Organizations**

12.2018 — 12.2019 Tokyo, Japan

#### Women Who Code Tokyo, Lead ≥

- Co-hosted a WWC Tokyo x Progate study together event for beginners
- Co-created the first WWC Tokyo brochure and T-shirts
- Regularly helped with organizing WWC Tokyo events and recruiting new volunteers
- Delivered a talk about career switching into the tech industry

#### **Education**

04.2019 - 08.2022 Remote 02.2017 - 04.2017 Tokyo

#### Launch School

A mastery-based school for software engineers: launchschool.com/employers

Le Wagon Tokyo

Web development bootcamp in Tokyo focused on web development using Rails.

04.2010 — 03.2014 Kanazawa, Japan **B.A. in Psychology,** Kanazawa University

#### Languages

# Malay

Native

#### **English**

- Full Working Proficiency
- (2010) TOEIC 975/990

## Japanese

- Full Working Proficiency
- (2013) JLPT N1
- (2009) |LPT Level 1
- (2009) JLPT Level 2